'"I want you to take out
your list of Red John suspects"
"and look at the names."
"I'll give you a moment."
"The names are..."
"Bret Stiles"
"Gale Bertram"
"Raymond Haffner"
"Reede Smith"
"Bob Kirkland"
"Sheriff Thomas McAllister"
"Brett Partridge."
"There."
"I'm going to start killing again.
Often."
"Until you catch me..."
"or I catch you."
- How did he do that?
- Huh?
That tape was made
two months ago.
Red John knew the names on the list
of suspects before you did.
I mean, how is that even possible?
Eh, it's a trick.
A trick how?
I don't know.
Lisbon.
Chief.
I'll be right there.
That was Bertram.
We have a case.
Huh?
- We have a case.
- Now?
Uh, I don't wanna work
right now, Lisbon.
I need to think.
We need to carry on as normal.
We don't wanna look freaked out.
I'm not freaked out.
- Yeah. Hi, guys.
- Hey, Sarge.
- Good to see you again.
- Nice to see you.
- How are things?
- It's been pretty busy.
Hey there.
- He can't say hello?
- Eh, it's a tough day.
So I understand you got the call
about three hours ago.
What do we got?
The victim's name
is Sandra Helvig.
She lives here with her fiancé.
That's Cody Benbow,
the baseball player.
"So he comes home from practice
and finds her lying right here."
"Looks like she's strangled
with her own scarf."
"Probably dead for a couple of hours.
We're waiting for the coroner."
The back window is broken
There's both jewelry
and cash missing.
We're thinking she came home
and surprised the burglar.
Well, besides the forced entry, I don't see
any obvious signs of a struggle here.
Hey, Cody, how much was stolen?
Dollar value?
I don't know, sir. Her engagement ring
alone was 50 grand. Um...
A couple hundred grand in total.
What's your batting average
this year?
Two sixty.
- What about last year?
- Three twelve.
Oh. What happened?
You came here
to talk about baseball?
Yeah, I'm trying to work here
and you're staring at me
like I have two heads.
Do I look like
I have two heads?
- Uh, no.
- No.
Sarge, why don't you and I go
outside, do our paperwork?
Cody, look at me.
I think it was you
that killed Sandra.
Sir, you are flat-out wrong.
She is the love of my life.
Why would I kill her?
You tell me.
There is no reason
in the world, sir.
No reason.
Okay, Cody. Fair enough.
I know when a man
is telling me the truth.
- Do you have any guns?
- Do I have any guns?
- Yeah.
- Y-yeah, yeah, I-I do.
Where? What kind?
- A couple of handguns or so in the safe.
- Show me.
What does guns
have to do with anything?
I'm sorry, but she was strangled.
Can you not see that?
Who's in charge here,
me or you?
Um, I just wanna see your guns.
I can search this place
from the roof to the basement.
- I can dig up the garden if I want to.
- O-okay, all right.
Just, just chill.
I'll show you my guns.
They're in the safe.
It's that way.
They loaded?
- Just the nine.
- Let me see.
Hmm.
Well, it doesn't look
like it's been fired.
Here's the thing, Cody.
Sandra wasn't coming home
when she was killed, was she?
She was leaving.
She was just about to walk
out the door when...
you got home.
She was leaving you.
No!
We've never been happier.
She packed her suitcases
left the engagement ring
on the table like you were nothing.
But you're Cody Benbow,
for God's sakes.
- No one can treat you like that.
- No.
And you got mad,
and you killed her.
Then you had to unpack
her suitcase
put her clothes
and her makeup away.
But you did it poorly.
Like a man putting away
a woman's things.
Are you serious? That's your proof?
That--that her closet's messy?
Yeah, you're right.
It's not really much, is it?
It's not proof.
Proof would be finding
the jewelry and the cash
that was taken from her.
But a sensible man like you
wouldn't actually throw
that money away, would they?
Even if they had the time.
A sensible man would
hide it someplace
that no one would think
to look.
Someplace close,
like the garden.
You buried it in the garden,
didn't you?
You shut your mouth now!
Shut your mouth.
I'll take that as a yes.
- Oh, no!
- "Gun! He's got a gun!"
Drop it! Don't be stupid!
Back off, or he's dead.
Okay, everyone just relax.
There is no need for violence.
The gun doesn't work.
I put peanuts in the chamber.
So just come on down
and arrest him.
- Drop it!
- Don't move!
Keep your hands
where we can see them!
Don't move!
"We have an officer down, we need
a Medevac to this location ASAP."
Secure his weapon.
I'm sorry.
Here he comes.
Oh, crap.
Just act naturally.
- Breathe.
- I am breathing.
Have you gone mad?
A-are you insane?
It-it's a serious question.
Are you asking her
or are you asking me?
'Cause speaking for myself,
the answer is no.
Lisbon--sane, not sane...
Sir, I fully recognize
that I failed in my duty
- to oversee Jane's behavior.
- Oh, stop. You did nothing wrong.
Agent Lisbon did wrong
when she failed
to stop you furnishing guns
to a man
who used those guns
to mow down a Sac P.D. officer.
It was a good plan
that went awry.
I said "Sorry."
She's not responsible.
That's her job.
Being responsible.
- I am responsible.
- Sac P.D. brass wants your blood.
So the question is,
should I suspend the both of you
- for a month or--
- Sir, that is not fair.
Allow me to complete
my thought.
Should I suspend you
or should I just send you
on an outta-town case
far away from the Sac P.D.?
The second option.
Oh?
I-I thought you might
prefer suspension.
It frees you up to focus
on Red John.
- I hear you're getting close.
- Oh, yeah?
Where'd you hear that?
Well, you can't keep secrets
around here.
There's a buzz all around
the building.
Jane's getting close, or thinks he is.
Well, are you?
Eh, we have some
fresh leads.
We're trying to keep them
a little quiet.
Oh, yeah. Mum's the word.
But if you do get close,
you will tell me first
'cause I need to be on the boat
when you catch that fish.
- Do we understand each other?
- Yes, sir.
I know that sometimes
I must appear calculating
even duplicitous to you
but please understand
it--it comes
with the job description.
I am many things
to many people.
We understand.
In the meantime...
get outta town.
Way outta town.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
No.
You're thinking
that if Bertram is Red John
he sent us out to the middle
of nowhere for a reason.
To get us out of the way
for when he makes his next move.
I am thinking about...
trains.
So what do we do?
- I don't know.
- Well, we have to do something.
Arrest them all, release
the names publicly--something.
Well, maybe that's what
Red John wants us to do.
We could at least keep Bertram
and the other seven suspects
under surveillance
if the rest of the team
was involved, if they knew.
No, no. We tell no one
about the list. No one.
Well, if Red John knows
about the list already--
Anyone else that knows
about the list will be in danger.
We tell no one.
I shouldn't have even told you.
Kinda beautiful and weird, huh?
All the flowers.
Hey, Partridge.
How long's the body
been here?
About 18 months, probably.
Uh...
We think he was a large male,
early 40s, maybe.
No teeth, no fingers.
Probably removed by whoever brought him
here to prevent identification.
But I bet if you cross-reference
that frat ring--
That's what she's doing.
Got you. Yeah.
"Hey, boss.
Brooke Yardley."
He was a Los Angeles
real estate developer, 46.
His wife reported him missing
in August of 2011.
I-I want you to run
a full profile on this guy ASAP.
Will do.
Hello, Mr. Yardley.
Who did this to ya?
Hmm?
How long until you're done
with forensics
and you pull this guy
outta here?
Delicate job. We'll be outta here
by tomorrow morning, probably.
Something wrong?
Wrong?
You've been really sullen
with me recently
and now you're staring
at me strangely
and I don't know why.
You truly don't know?
No.
Hmm.
Yardley was a wheeler-dealer
salesman type.
No criminal record,
but he had his share
of law and tax problems.
Bankrupt twice.
"His car was found abandoned
in Los Angeles"
"a couple weeks
after his disappearance."
- Any standout enemies?
- "Not off his paper trail."
Cho and Rigsby are driving
to L.A. in the morning
to talk to the wife and son.
All right. Jane and I need
to stay out here
near the crime scene
till the body's dug up.
We'll give you a call
when we find someplace to stay.
"Sure."
What's your take on Partridge?
If he is Red John,
he's a very good actor.
He would have to be,
wouldn't he?
Wait. Slow down.
Let's turn here.
This looks interesting.
- Thanks, hon.
- See you tomorrow, Sonya.
Hey, folks.
- And what can I get you?
- Tea, please.
Oolong, preferably.
Uh... Well... Just tea.
Some loosely scrambled eggs
on rye toast.
One strip of bacon
- and one sausage, thanks.
- Okay.
- Coffee and muffin.
- Okay. Coming right up.
You've heard
about the dead guy, I guess.
Yeah, sure.
Everybody has.
We're with the CBI.
We're investigating the case.
Yeah. Sorry, I--
I didn't mean to scare you.
Oh, no, no. I--
I'm not scared.
I just... I've had
a bad feeling forever
like I knew there was something
evil out there.
I knew it.
Didn't I, Hec?
Uh-huh.
Huh.
Hmm, come to think...
that I'm right?
My gosh.
I mean, I always knew
I had a psychic gift
but this is damn spooky.
Psychic gift?
Excellent.
Tell me, uh, will I enjoy
your eggs?
You betcha.
We'll see.
You're right, Sonya.
These are enjoyable eggs.
Room for improvement,
but very enjoyable.
Good.
What are we doing, Jane?
I'm eating eggs.
You're staring at a dry muffin.
- We need a plan.
- I've been thinking about that.
In the meantime, Red John
is gonna kill again.
Yeah, probably.
Jane, I'm scared.
- He's not psychic.
- Well, that's not what scares me.
- Well, no, that scares me, too.
- There's no such thing.
I'm scared because I've never seen you
like this before.
It's like you don't know
what to do next.
Next?
Well, pecan pie.
- Funny. Funny. I'm serious.
- So am I.
- We need help.
- No.
- Hey, boss.
- "Hey, we need to talk."
"Are you alone?"
Y-yeah. Well, I mean,
Wayne's with me.
Call me back as soon
as you're on your own.
Hello? Hello?
Lost her.
Bad signal in the desert.
- She'll call right back.
- Yep.
- Give me a moment, huh?
- Sure.
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
"You cannot tell anyone
what I'm about to tell you."
Okay.
Jane has worked out that
Red John is one of seven men.
But Red John also knows
the seven names on Jane's list.
- How?
- "We don't know."
It's like he's read Jane's mind
which has made Jane
paranoid, understandably.
"He doesn't want anyone
to know about the list of names."
"He doesn't know I'm talking
to you right now."
He thinks whoever knows
about the names is in danger
and he's probably right.
But I have a strong feeling
we need to do something
and I need your help.
- "Do you want me to continue?"
- Yes.
"Thank you."
I'm gonna give you
the seven names
and I need you to put
a G.P.S. bug
on each of their cell phones.
But you need to do it secretly.
Tell no one.
- Can you do that?
- Yes, I can
but when are you gonna tell Jane?
When the time is right.
Okay, I guess. Um...
Let me get a pen and paper.
No, I don't want you
to write anything down.
- Everything okay?
- Sure, of course. I, um...
spoke to Lisbon.
I have work to do.
Work? Now?
- What's so urgent?
- Oh...
You know Lisbon.
No sense of time.
You go on home.
I'll see you there.
What's going on, Grace?
Nothing.
- Something wrong?
- No.
What do you mean?
You're acting weird
like you're keeping something
from me.
What?
No, dude.
What would I be keeping
from you?
- You're acting weird.
- Weird, like how?
Like you can't look me
in the eye.
Yes, I can.
- You happy now?
- No. What's going on, Wayne?
Am I intruding?
Are you sure it's my husband?
- Mrs. Yardley, we--
- Madison.
Madison. I'm sorry.
We're dealing
with a skeleton here
so we can't be sure of ID
until DNA test results are done.
But we think so, yes.
Oh, thank God.
Well, don't get me wrong
I loved Brooke very much
but I've known in my heart
he's been dead for some time now.
He would never have run away
without a word.
It's just good
to finally know the truth.
I've been in the most
hellish limbo.
Records indicate he had started
divorce proceedings.
Yes. It was a mutual decision.
You can love someone very much
and not be able to live with them.
What was the problem?
Oh, Brooke was a dog.
Pathological womanizer.
I knew it when I married him.
I'm his third wife. Duh.
But he was so charming
and witty and handsome.
He cheated on you.
Cheating would involve deception.
He never tried to deceive me.
Some would call that good motive
for killing him.
Well, I didn't.
But I know who did
kill him
if you wanna know.
I told the police two years ago,
but they weren't interested.
"No body, no crime",
they said.
So you know who killed him.
A man called Arek Green.
He owns nightclubs
across the border.
Brooke went to a meeting
with Arek in Mexicali
and that was the last anyone
ever saw Brooke.
And why would Mr. Green have reason
to kill your husband?
Arek owed Brooke something
around $100,000
on a property deal
and didn't wanna pay.
Brooke was going to sue him.
That's motive, isn't it?
This is my stepson Gavin.
He lives here also.
These are police of some kind.
They found your father's body.
Oh.
Really? Where?
Buried in the desert.
How squalid.
- Murder, was it?
- That's our supposition, yes.
Well, I'd take a good, long look
at this one.
She's perfectly capable of murder.
Too lazy, perhaps, but she could've
summoned a burst of energy.
She did so despise
my poor, dear father.
You are a bitter, twisted
little fantasist.
We had our battles,
but I loved that man.
Oh! Dishonest crap.
These are professional
policemen, Madison.
They can see right through you.
Okay.
Returning to Arek Green...
When was this meeting
in Mexicali, exactly?
July 10, two years ago.
I apologize for my stepson.
When Brooke is officially dead,
his will is enforceable
and Gavin will have to leave
my house.
Finally.
Hence the anger.
Oh, don't think for a second
I won't dispute
every inch of that will.
Oh, I know you will.
You're such a child.
God, I can't believe I ever let you
have sex with me.
Please.
You were practically begging me.
I am so sorry.
I blame his mother.
Now she was a piece of work.
Don't you say a word about my mother
you conniving little slut.
- Hey, folks--
- I will talk about who the hell I like.
Your mother
was a cold-hearted bitch!
Okay. Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Let's just take a breath.
Low heat, then a little water.
Keeps the eggs
nice and loose.
I've been cooking eggs
for 20 years.
Oh, so your cup's full.
Can't learn any more, huh?
- Not about eggs.
- Okay.
"Bon appétit."
Damn.
Jane.
Come here?
So both Yardley's son and wife
are still possible suspects.
But the wife says the last time
she saw Yardley
he was heading down
to Mexicali
to demand money outta
some shady businessman--
Guy named Arek Green.
He's got a criminal record,
underworld connections
And right now, we're about
a hundred miles from Mexicali.
Sounds like a lead.
Yeah, I'm thinking we should go
and talk to this guy Arek Green.
Yeah, I-I'm gonna stay here.
You go.
You can manage
on your own, right?
- Of course I can, but--
- Well, I-I like the quiet here.
The desert helps me think.
You know what?
I'll stay.
Cho and Rigsby can go
to Mexicali.
- Don't trust me alone, huh?
- I never have.
I'm gonna go and run
some calls.
Sure.
Boss, the wires are up.
- All of them?
- Yep.
G.P.S. and audio on all seven
Red John suspects.
Good work.
Okay, we watch them like hawks.
We log everywhere they go, 24/7.
- Will do.
- And remember, do not--
I-I know. Tell nobody.
That's a shame.
Yardley was good people.
Mr. Green, we're told you and Yardley
were in a business dispute.
Yeah, I mean, you know...
Yard loved drama.
But we're old friends
ten years now--
and it was nothing.
It seems like you were the last person
to see him alive.
And you owed him $100,000.
Which I gave to him. In cash.
Last time I saw him,
he was a happy man.
- Very happy.
- You get a receipt?
You know, it wasn't
that kind of transaction.
Uh-huh. Go on.
Look, I pay my debts.
I heard he vanished, I thought he went
somewhere like Brazil or something
so he didn't have to share
the money with the old lady.
Now you're telling me he's dead.
I gotta assume
the loopy bitch did it.
Or that wacko son.
Have you met those two?
Oh, you did?
So you know.
So you think
it's either the greedy wife
the angry son,
or the shady business partner?
Looks that way.
I think we should get 'em out here
take a look at 'em.
How are we gonna do that,
arrest them all?
Well, tell them we're gonna
find out
where the $100,000 cash is.
They'll come.
Well, what if there
was no 100 grand in cash?
Well, if there wasn't, the wife
and the son don't know it
and the shady business partner
has to pretend there was, right?
- I guess.
- Yeah.
They're here. Now what?
I think a simple seance
should do the trick.
- Seriously?
- Seriously.
Welcome. Madison.
Gavin. My name is Patrick Jane.
This is Agent Lisbon.
Thanks for coming all the way
out here to help us.
Hey, Van Pelt.
Hey, Jane.
So where's the money you promised?
Have a seat.
Um, try the eggs.
All will be revealed
in very good time.
I just need to have a quick word
with my colleagues.
Could you give us a minute, please?
- What?
- She knows about the list.
Yes, but only Grace.
Nobody else.
Now we can keep an eye
on the suspects.
You bugged their phones.
Yes.
Red John will know what you've done
and he will use it against us.
He will lead you
wherever he wants to.
I am not naive.
We'll act with that possibility in mind.
But it's better to have the information
available to us.
- It's better than doing nothing at all.
- No, no, no.
I-I told you--
Tell no one! I told you!
You told me?
You are not my boss.
This is my case.
Red John is my case.
You work for me.
Oh, come on, please,
Lisbon, don't be childish.
- Don't be arrogant!
- You are out of your depth.
- You can't--
- You can't tell me what to do
because I don't think
you know what you're doing yourself.
I have to do what I have to do
to do my job.
Now I'm going back to Sacramento
to keep an eye on the suspects.
You can do whatever
you want.
Grace, you're in charge
until Cho gets here.
- After that, he's in charge.
- Okay, boss.
Wait!
Hey. Hey, Lisbon. Lisbon!
Mr. Jane, agent Van Pelt,
this is Arek Green.
Good. Nice to meet you,
Mr. Green.
Why don't you go inside
the diner, take a seat?
I just need to talk
to my colleagues.
You told them about the list.
No.
I told Rigsby.
Look, I had to.
He thought I was having an affair.
She was acting weird.
You told Cho.
Well, he can't be the only member
of the team that doesn't know.
Come on, that's not fair.
I'm not gonna tell anybody.
Lisbon was only doing
what she thought was best.
You have to make up with her.
Thanks.
So what's the plan?
Well, if anyone tries
to kill me, shoot 'em.
Okay, hello, everybody.
My name is Patrick Jane.
I'm with the CBI.
We're here to solve a murder.
Uh, Sonya, will you help me?
I need your psychic gifts.
Me? Oh, no, no.
I don't think so.
Yeah, please. Come take
a good look at these three people.
They all had reasons to kill
Brooke Yardley.
Are you kidding me?
What reason did I have?
If you're innocent, hush, please.
Uh, you knew that Yardley
was out there, didn't you?
You heard him.
He spoke to you.
I guess, in a way.
Yardley can tell us
which one of these three
is the guilty one,
just like he told you
that he was out there.
He can?
- Uh, this is very amusing, but I'm...
- Quiet.
Thank you, Cho.
He spoke to your subconscious
and we need to speak to him
in that way.
This will do.
Uh... Would you just put
your hand just like that?
Just... relax.
Just like that. Okay.
Now close your eyes.
Think about Brooke Yardley.
Ask him to tell us
what he wants to tell us.
Think deeply.
Okay, and when you're ready...
let your hand fall.
"L". Uh, Van Pelt, would you write
these down, please?
Keep thinking about Yardley.
What does he wanna say?
And when you feel it...
do it again.
"U".
And again.
"K".
"E".
"12"?
"27".
Luke 12:27?
Is there anyone connected
to the case named Luke?
Maybe it's the, uh, bible verse?
Luke 12:27. Wh--what does--
what does that say?
"Consider the lilies,
how they grow."
- "They toil not..."
- "Neither do they spin."
What does that have to do
with anything?
I don't know.
Wait a minute.
"How they grow".
Yardley had lilies on his grave.
Well, flowers, anyway.
Uh, not--not the normal kinda flowers
you'd see in the desert.
And grass, for that matter.
That's what he's trying
to tell us.
How did those flowers
end up there?
And--and how
did they get water?
Well, there's only one
logical explanation.
The body was in a block of ice.
A block of ice that was carried
in a flat-bed truck
that normally carries
garden supplies
like flower and grass seeds.
Seeds that stuck to a block of ice.
- Clever.
- Yes, but...
But ice melts very fast
in the desert
so that block couldn't have been moved
very far from where it started.
What we're looking
for is someplace
close to the crime scene
where they have a large
commercial freezer.
- Like in a diner.
- Yes.
But why would anyone
at the diner
wanna kill Brooke Yardley?
Yeah, I...
Hello.
Well, unless, of course,
he was...
flashing all that money
he had.
And he was that kinda guy.
You know, a showoff
and a ladies' man, right?
Yes.
I bet he hit on you, Sonya.
Yeah?
Well, you said no, of course.
Then he offered you money.
"And you're a good woman
but everyone has their price."
"Your boyfriend Hector
is the jealous type."
"But Brooke was a big man
so Hec probably got Mac to help out."
Then the three of you argued
over what to do next.
Do you let Yardley go, or do you
kill him and take the money?
Your biggest mistake--
you let him hear you.
- "What are you doing?"
- "We have to kill him."
"He knew he was gonna die"
"so he made sure
his body was identifiable"
"by swallowing his ring."
- "Mac's right. We gotta kill him!"
- "No! Mac! No!"
This is garbage.
Fantasy.
You have no evidence.
This from a man wearing a hat
that says
"Landscaping and gardening supplies."
There's plenty of other guys
that work at garden supply stores.
And plenty of other diners
that got freezers.
Yes, but this is the only one
with a fancy new sign on the highway.
How much did that cost you?
It-it was them!
They killed him. I--
They tried to keep me quiet.
- I had nothing to do with it.
- Sonya, shut up!
Book 'em, guys.
Not now, Jane.
"This is Teresa Lisbon.
I can't take your call right now."
"Please leave a message
after the beep."
Uh, hi, Lisbon.
Um... Call me.
Uh... I'm sorry we argued.
I just, uh...
I realized, um...
Yeah, just--just call me.
We'll chat.
Lisbon.
"We have an anonymous tip
directed to your unit."
"A person or persons in distress
at 5570 West Huron."
"At 5570 West Huron.
Okay, I got it."
That's weird.
Brett Partridge is there.
This is Agent Lisbon
with the CBI.
I need Sac P.D. to roll code
to 5570 West Huron.
Immediate assistance,
5570 West Huron.
Yeah, no, I understand. When do
you think they're gonna be here?
All right.
Thanks for nothing.
Damn it.
"This is Teresa Lisbon.
I can't take your call right now."
"Please leave a message
after the beep."
Where are you?
Call me.
Oh, my God.
Partridge? Partridge?
T...
T... Tiger.
Tiger.
Uh, excuse me,
have you seen Lisbon?
Nope. Haven't seen her.
Ah, great.
Lisbon, finally.
"Sorry, Patrick. Teresa can't come
to the phone right now."
"Can I take a message?"
No?
"Well, I'll tell her you called."
Wait--